

New Delhi, India

🗷 hitesh.kumar61@yahoo.com | 😭 www.hitesh.one | 🖸 hiteshhedwig | 🛅 hiteshkumar17 | 💆 @rnnishard

"A healthy mind is an inquisitive mind."

Personal Profile

As a self-taught and passionate individual, I am eager to pursue a Master's in Al. Currently, I am a seasoned Deep Learning Engineer with over three years of experience in AI. I am keen to delve deeper into research areas and push the boundaries for perception strategies on autonomous vehicles and robotics. My strong determination and vision for research have been further enhanced after working on projects involving Autonomous Vehicles, AI for Smart Cities, and Mars Rover prototype-like challenging and fruitful themes.

Research Interests

- · Perception for Autonomous driving
- · Computer Vision on Robotics
- Deep Learning
- Visual odometry

Skills

Platform/Tools Linux, Docker, Google Cloud, ROS, CMake

Frameworks OpenCV, Pytorch, Tensorflow, CUDA, Numpy, Matplotlib, FFMPEG, Git

ELP USB Cameras, IP Cameras, Nvidia Jetson Series, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, 2D Radar, 4D Radar, 2D Lidar, 3D Lidar, Intel Sensor/Hardware

Realsense, IR Sensor, Ultrasonic Sensor, Hall effect Sensor etc.

Programming C++, Python, Golang Languages English, Hindi, Korean

Relevant Professional Experience

Euler Motors (EV startup) New Delhi, India

DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER, COMPUTER VISION (MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF - I) - AUTONOMOUS R&D

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Key contributor in building real-time ADAS (Advanced Driver Assistance Systems) using pure C++; optimized for Nvidia Jetson Nano. Implemented forward collision warning and automatic emergency braking system.
- Led raw data curation and established semi-automatic data annotation system; expedited team processes, saving over two days.
- Trained and optimized lightweight object detection and segmentation models; achieved over 60% and 50% model size reduction, enhancing low-latency performance.
- Spearheaded the creation of a model versioning system from scratch, fostering improved model deployment and management practices for the whole team.
- Initiated and maintained production-level documented C++ code (ROS) for ADAS system; achieved <100ms inference, 10Hz alert generation, and reduced hardware costs by over 65%.

SynergyLabs (AI startup) New Delhi, India July. 2021 - Aug. 2022

DEEP LEARNING ENGINEER - R&D

SynergyLabs (AI startup)

- Trained and customized classification & object detection models with data augmentation; achieved 14% increase in performance.
- Designed and implemented automatic number plate detection pipeline in Python to flag overspeeding vehicle.
- Developed Vehicle Detection System deployed on highways; attained <6% speed error in detection.
- Co-developed attention-based OCR model for license plates; achieved over 95% accuracy on standard plates.

DEEP LEARNING INTERN - R&D Feb. 2021 - July. 2021

- Collaborated with founder in developing 'Automatic Traffic Counter System (ATCS)'; deployed across 300+ locations.
- Curated dataset for MobilenetV2 fine-tuning; reduced model size to 2MB, achieving 30% reduction.
- Debugged issues and maintained error resolution documentation, saving teammates 3+ hours.
- Developed ATCS product configuration UI with PyQT; reduced manual effort by 3x.

Education

Delhi Technological University (formerly DCE)

Delhi, India

New Delhi, India

2016-2020

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

• Relevant courses like "(PE413) Robotics and Automation", "(MOOC403) Introduction to Self Driving Cars".

Tech Activity_

Society of Robotics DTU India

Core Member

- Key organizer for University tech-fest; managed events like Robosoccer, Robofight.
- Mentored juniors in computer vision fundamentals and career pathways.

InfernoDTU (Project Mars Rover Prototype)

India 2018 - 2020

2016 - 2018

SOFTWARE HEAD (AUTONOMOUS)

- Led autonomous tech team (5+ members) in developing Mars Rover Prototype's autonomous features for competitive events.
- Utilized ROS in C++/Python for remote rover navigation.
- · Implemented traditional computer vision techniques using OpenCV for obstacle detection and collision avoidance.

InfernoDTU (Gokart)IndiaMember2017 - 2018

• Developed TensorFlow-based CNN model for animal detection on roads.

- Designed real-time pedestrian detection algorithm using OpenCV for Raspberry Pi 4b.
- Enhanced lane detection algorithm for improved performance.

Key Technical Projects

Simplified Visual Odometry [LINK]

India

GITHUB

2023

· Created a documented roadmap of the core fundamentals for visual odometry to help me and others.

Structure from Motion - Clean [LINK]

India

GITHUB

2023

An attempt to write clean and readable code for SfM pipeline unlike all the other implementation

ReID Tracking using yolov8 [LINK]

India

GITHLIB

2023

Integrated yolov8 with bytetrack and strongsort tracking algorithm to address re-identification problem.

Light object detection [LINK]

India

GITHUB

2023

An in-development package which aim to wrap up the lightweight object detection model for edge device inference.

Self driving vision stack [LINK]

India

GITHUB

2020

· A simple primary self driving vision stack including Lane detection, Car detection, Traffic light detection, Pedestrian detection.

Research Papers_

Analytical and Computational Modelling of Go-Kart Powertrains - Hitesh Kumar, Aditya Natu, Kunal

2020 **Mathur**, International Journal of Mechanical and Production Engineering Research and Development (IJMPERD)

Estimation Of Surface Roughness in turning operations using Multivariate Polynomial Regression -

Hrishabh Jha, Ashutosh Panpalia, Devanshu Suneja, Geetanshu Ashpilya, Hitesh Kumar, and Vijay Gautam, Advances in Industrial and Production Engineering

MooC

- 2023 Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris (ongoing), Coursera
- 2023 Visual Perception for Self-Driving Cars (University of Toronto) (ongoing), Coursera
- 2020 Robotics: Aerial Robotics (University of Pennsylvania), Coursera
- 2019 Introduction To Self Driving Cars (University of Toronto), Coursera
- 2020 Data Visualization, Kaggle
- 2020 AWS Machine Learning Foundation Course, Coursera
- 2022 Robotics: Perception (University of Pennsylvania), Coursera
- 2019 Internet History, Technology, and Security, Coursera